<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantum-Computing on Live and let Learn</title>
    <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/tags/quantum-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantum-Computing on Live and let Learn</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 14:05:30 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://liveandletlearn.net/tags/quantum-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flipping a Coin: An Analogy for simulated Quantum Computing Limitations</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/flipping-coin-analogy-quantum-computing-limitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 14:05:30 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/flipping-coin-analogy-quantum-computing-limitation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love chatting about science with whoever I find myself with and learning together through those interactions. A few times I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself talking about Quantum Computing and specifically discussing why quantum computers are required for quantum calculations. That is, restating the question, &lt;strong&gt;why can&amp;rsquo;t we just simulate quantum calculations on the powerful computers we have today&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The quick answer is that the &lt;strong&gt;amount of data (numbers) required to do those quantum calculations grows way too large very quickly&lt;/strong&gt; as the size of the calculation grows. So yes, we can simulate very simple quantum calculations that require only a few quantum bits, or qubits, but as the number of qubits grows, that data required for the calculation grows too large for our computers to handle - at least with the current math that we use for quantum calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live and Let Learn with Rust, Quantum Computing and Piloting aeroplanes</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/live-and-let-learn-piloting-rust-and-quantum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 16:25:25 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/live-and-let-learn-piloting-rust-and-quantum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In mid 2022 I was presented with an &lt;strong&gt;amazing opportunity&lt;/strong&gt; through no effort of my own: VMware, the company I worked for, announced it was being acquired by a non-remote, non-open-source-oriented multi-national in a somewhat lengthy 18 month process. As a fully-remote staff engineer on an open-source project &lt;strong&gt;I estimated a 75 to 90 percent probability that I&amp;rsquo;d receive a redundancy in around 18 months time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A redundancy, really? An amazing opportunity? This post is a personal reflection and reminder to my future self to step back and evaluate the potential opportunities that a situation provides. I&amp;rsquo;m currently using this opportunity to &lt;strong&gt;weave three passions of mine into a possible future of software engineering with Rust on quantum computing projects and piloting aeroplanes on the side&lt;/strong&gt;. Sure, reality may force me to compromise in one way or another in time, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m leaving my options open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
