<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Live and let Learn</title>
    <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Live and let Learn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 11:40:02 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://liveandletlearn.net/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubeapps on Tanzu Mission Control via Pinniped</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/kubeapps-on-tanzu-mission-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 11:40:02 +1100</pubDate>
      <author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/kubeapps-on-tanzu-mission-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been able to run &lt;a href=&#34;https://liveandletlearn.net/post/kubeapps-on-tkg-management-cluster/&#34;&gt;Kubeapps in a multi-cluster setup on various Kubernetes clusters&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, but this was dependent on the Kubeapps&amp;rsquo; user being authenticated in a way that all the clusters trust. Up until now, this meant having all the clusters &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/access-authn-authz/authentication/#configuring-the-api-server&#34;&gt;configured to trust the same OIDC identity provider&lt;/a&gt;, which is not possible in some Kubernetes environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particularly, this meant we were unable to demonstrate multi-cluster Kubeapps with clusters created by &lt;a href=&#34;https://tanzu.vmware.com/mission-control&#34;&gt;Tanzu Mission Control&lt;/a&gt; since we can&amp;rsquo;t specify API server options, such as OIDC configuration, when creating a cluster in TMC. But that requirement has now changed thanks to a new project called &lt;a href=&#34;https://pinniped.dev/&#34;&gt;Pinniped&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubeapps on a TKG Management Cluster</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/kubeapps-on-tkg-management-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 11:01:36 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/kubeapps-on-tkg-management-cluster/</guid>
      <description>This is part two of a series detailing the steps required to run Kubeapps on a VMware TKG management cluster (on AWS) configured to allow users to deploy applications to multiple workload clusters, using the new multicluster support in Kubeapps. Though details will differ, a similar configuration works on other non-TKG multicluster setups as well.
The first post described setting up your VMware TKG management cluster with two OpenIDConnect-enabled workload clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (TKG) with OpenID Connect - First Experience</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/tanzu-kubernetes-grid-tkg-first-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 10:01:03 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/tanzu-kubernetes-grid-tkg-first-experience/</guid>
      <description>Andres and I have been doing quite a bit of feature work in Kubeapps over the past months at VMware and one of the key features that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on personally is enabling Kubeapps users to deploy applications not only on the cluster on which Kubeapps is installed, but to multiple other clusters as well.
Enter VMware Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (TGK): an &amp;ldquo;Enterprise-ready Kubernetes runtime which streamlines operations across multi-cloud infrastructure&amp;rdquo;, so naturally I was keen to test out running Kubeapps on TKG and deploying applications to a set of TKG-managed clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual booting the Dell XPS13 (9365) with linux</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/dell-xps13-9365-dual-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 19:50:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/dell-xps13-9365-dual-boot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dell.com/au/p/xps-13-9365-2-in-1-laptop/pd?oc=z511203au&amp;amp;model_id=xps-13-9365-2-in-1-laptop&#34;&gt;Dell XPS13 (9365)&lt;/a&gt; (thanks to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitnami.com/&#34;&gt;Bitnami&lt;/a&gt; for whom I now work) which comes with Windows 10 preinstalled. I was
aware when purchasing that &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugzilla.kernel.org/show_bug.cgi?id=192591&#34;&gt;suspend on Linux is not yet working&lt;/a&gt;
(thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://perltricks.com/article/laptop-review--dell-xps-13-2-in-1--9365-/&#34;&gt;David Farrell&lt;/a&gt;. As of &lt;a href=&#34;#suspendfix&#34;&gt;Aug 2017 suspend is fixed&lt;/a&gt;,
see below), as well as other functionality (autorotate, pen integration etc.)
and so was keen to have a few options to
work on this machine&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>