<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rust on Live and let Learn</title>
    <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/tags/rust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rust on Live and let Learn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 16:25:25 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://liveandletlearn.net/tags/rust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Live and Let Learn with Rust, Quantum Computing and Piloting aeroplanes</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/live-and-let-learn-piloting-rust-and-quantum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 16:25:25 +1100</pubDate><author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/live-and-let-learn-piloting-rust-and-quantum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In mid 2022 I was presented with an &lt;strong&gt;amazing opportunity&lt;/strong&gt; through no effort of my own: VMware, the company I worked for, announced it was being acquired by a non-remote, non-open-source-oriented multi-national in a somewhat lengthy 18 month process. As a fully-remote staff engineer on an open-source project &lt;strong&gt;I estimated a 75 to 90 percent probability that I&amp;rsquo;d receive a redundancy in around 18 months time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A redundancy, really? An amazing opportunity? This post is a personal reflection and reminder to my future self to step back and evaluate the potential opportunities that a situation provides. I&amp;rsquo;m currently using this opportunity to &lt;strong&gt;weave three passions of mine into a possible future of software engineering with Rust on quantum computing projects and piloting aeroplanes on the side&lt;/strong&gt;. Sure, reality may force me to compromise in one way or another in time, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m leaving my options open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day03 Tokens, Enums and Docstrings</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/advent-of-code-2023/day03-enums-and-docstrings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 06:45:18 +1100</pubDate><author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/advent-of-code-2023/day03-enums-and-docstrings/</guid>
      <description>The Day 03 challenge involves the calculating whether a character symbol is adjacent to a part number in a two dimensional map, such as:&#xA;467..114.. ...*...... ..35..633. ......#... 617*...... .....+.58. ..592..... ......755. ...$.*.... .664.598.. and then doing things with the part numbers.&#xA;To calculate whether a symbol is adjacent to a part number we&amp;rsquo;re going to need:&#xA;the position of each symbol, the position of each number, the length of the token for each number.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day02 Copilot and Vanilla Parsing</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/advent-of-code-2023/day02-copilot-and-vanilla-parsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 06:13:31 +1100</pubDate><author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/advent-of-code-2023/day02-copilot-and-vanilla-parsing/</guid>
      <description>After refreshing my knowledge of the rust parsing library &amp;rsquo;nom&amp;rsquo; with the day01 challenge, I was keen to do the second challenge without, simply using the standard library&amp;rsquo;s string manipulation and default parsing for this simpler parsing problem.&#xA;At the same time, I was keen to work more with GitHub Copilot since I&amp;rsquo;ve not been able to use copilot at my most recent job due to potential legal issues.&#xA;The Elf&amp;rsquo;s game for day 02 consists of pulling out multiple combinations of red, green and blue balls from a sack - and the parsing looks quite straight forward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 01 - a Rust Parsing Exercise With Nom</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/advent-of-code-2023/day01-a-rust-parsing-exercise-with-nom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 13:51:15 +1100</pubDate><author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/advent-of-code-2023/day01-a-rust-parsing-exercise-with-nom/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been quite some time since I&amp;rsquo;ve taken time to enjoy coding challenges primarily for the fun of it. Over the next months, I&amp;rsquo;m keen to work my way through the 2023 Advent of Code - a fun set of problems created by Eric Wastl strung together with a seasonal story - and write up a bit about my own learning and fun.&#xA;For me it&amp;rsquo;s a chance to keep improving my fluency with various Rust libraries and tools (start learning the Rust programming language here!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2023</title>
      <link>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/advent-of-code-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 13:46:54 +1100</pubDate><author>absoludity&#43;lll@gmail.com (Michael Nelson)</author>
      <guid>https://liveandletlearn.net/post/advent-of-code-2023/</guid>
      <description>Advent of code 2023 - I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually collect some general info about the libraries that I&amp;rsquo;m using repeatedly, as well as some other more general learning, but the details are in each post below.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
